Herz, John H.; Papers ger015
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Organizations & institutions: correspondence, minutes, publications, newsletters, 1943-2002; 4; 73 file folders
  - The Rockefeller Foundation (including Kenneth Thompson), 1959-1972 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 2)
  - Rutgers University, 1967-1968 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 3)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1984 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 3)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1963-1964 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 3)
  - Sparkasse der Stadt Marburg, 1980-1996 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 4)
  - Stiftung Volkswagenwerk, 1976-1984 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 5)
  - Syracuse University, 1964-1965 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 6)
  - Teachers Retirement System, 1975-1976 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 6)
  - Tufts University, The Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, 1962-1963 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 6)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1975-1988 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 7)
  - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 1969; 1998 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 7)
  - United States Information Agency, 1959 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 7)
  - United States Institute of Peace, 1993 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 7)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1959-1960 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 8)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1967-1968 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 8)
  - University of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1967 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 8)
  - W.E.B. Dubois Memorial Committee, 1968 (Box 7 (4-Organizations & institutions: ), Folder 8)
- Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of monographs, textbooks, 1952-1982; 5; 55 file folders
  This series contains manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of Herz's longer works, including Major Foreign Powers, Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century and From Dictatorship to Democracy. Also present in this series are reviews of many of Herz's major publications, 1931-1982.
  - Major Foreign Powers (1952) - outlines, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 9)
  - Major Foreign Powers - "The Government of Germany", Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 10-11)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed., 1972) - "Introduction" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 12)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Great Britain" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 13)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "France" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 14)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Germany" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 15-16)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Germany" - page proofs, with corr, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 17)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Soviet Union" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 18)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Conclusion" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 19)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Bibliography" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 20)
  - Major Foreign Powers (6th ed.) - "Index" - galley proofs, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 21)
  - International Politics in the Atomic Age (1959) - note cards, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 22)
  - Government and Politics in the Twentieth Centur y (2nd ed., 1965) - page mock-ups, Undated (Box 7 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 23)
  - Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century (3rd ed., 1973) - corrected proofs, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 1-2)
  - Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century - revisions to 3rd edition, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 3-4)
  - Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century - galley proofs, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 5)
  - German Constitutional Documents Since 1871 (1970) - galley proofs, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 6)
  - Staatenwelt und Weltpolitik. Aufsätze zur internationalen Politik im Nuklearzeitalter (1974) - "Einleitung", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 7)
  - Staatenwelt und Weltpolitik. Aufsätze zur internationalen Politik im Nuklearzeitalter - typescripts, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 8)
  - Staatenwelt und Weltpolitik. Aufsätze zur internationalen Politik im Nuklearzeitalter - page proofs, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 9)
  - The Nation-State and the Crisis of World Politics (1976) - page proofs, Undated (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 10)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy (1982) - John H. Herz: "Introduction", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 11)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - John H. Herz: "Denazification and Related Policies in Germany", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 12)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - John H. Herz: "Denazification and Related Policies in Germany". Early versions, Undated; Typescripts (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 13)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Karlheinz Niclauss: "Political Reconstruction at Bonn", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 14)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Michael Fichter: "Non-State Organizations and the Problem of Redemocratization", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 15)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Jutta B. Lange - Quassowski: "Coming to Terms with the Nazi Past", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 16)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Giuseppe DiPalma: "Four Other Democracies Arise from World War II", Undated; Typescript (Box 8 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 17)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Frederick C. Engelmann. "How Austria Has Coped with Two Dictatorial Legacies", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 1)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Roy C. Macridis: "France: From Vichy to the Fourth Republic", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 2)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Arthur E. Tiedmann: "Japan Disposes of Military Dictatorship", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 3)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Eduard Malefakis: "Going with Mediterranean Styles of Dictatorship", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 4)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Kenneth Maxwell: "The Emergence of Portuguese Democracy", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 5)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - Harry J. Psomiades: "Greece: From the Colonels' Rule to Democracy", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 6)
  - From Dictatorship to Democracy - John H. Herz: "Conclusion", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 7)
  - Reviews of Herz' writings, 5.36 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 11-23)
    - Die Identität des Staates, 1931 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 8)
    - Bristler, Eduard.Völkerrechtslehre des Nationalsozialismus, 1938 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 9)
    - Political Realism and Political Idealism, 1951 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 10)
    - Major Foreign Powers, 1952-1972 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 11)
    - International Politics in the Atomic Age, 1959; 1962 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 12)
    - International Politics in the Atomic Age - reviews A - Z, Undated (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 13)
    - Weltpolitik im Atomzeitalter (1961) - short reviews, Undated (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 14)
    - Weltpolitik im Atomzeitalter - reviews A - Z, Undated (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 15)
    - Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century, 1961-1973 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 16)
    - Regierungsformen des 20. Jahrhunderts, 1962 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 17)
    - Bennett, John C.Nuclear Weapons and the Conflict of Conscience - section by Herz, 1962 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 18)
    - German Constitutional Documents Since 1871, 1970 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 19)
    - Staatenwelt und Weltpolitik, 1974 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 20)
    - The Nation-State and the Crisis of International Politics - reviews, 1976 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 21)
    - From Dictatorship to Democracy - reviews, 1982 (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 22)
    - References to Herz in works by others, Undated (Box 9 (5-Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of ), Folder 23)
- Essayistic writings, poetry, short prose, 1930-2005; 6; 305 file folders
  This series is divided into three sub-series. The first two sub-series (1) Essayistic, prose, poetry (133 file folders) and (2) Letters to the Editor (83 file folders) are arranged chronologically, while the third sub-series (3) Herz's reviews of works by others (89 file folders) is arranged alphabetically by the author of the work reviewed. This series contains a nearly complete set of Herz's published essayistic writings, as well as a small number of unpublished essays, poems and stories.
  - Notes: Expropriation in International Law, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 24)
  - Notes: International Law, Legal Theory, Theory of International Politics, etc., Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 25)
  - Notes: Propaganda in Government and International Relations, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 26)
  - Notes: U.S. Government, American Foreign Policy, American History, American Political Thought, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 27)
  - Proposed collection of essays on Germany. Outline, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 28)
  - "Denazifying or 'Renazifying' the American Zone of Germany?", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 29)
  - "The English Balance of Power Policy", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 30)
  - "Entrance, Exit and What To Do In-Between. Towards an Ethics of Survival", unpublished, Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 31)
  - "Gedanken zu Hermann Brochs 'Tod des Vergil'", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 32)
  - "Gedanken zu Hermann Hesses 'Glasperlenspiel'", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 33)
  - "The German Perception of America". Notes, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 34)
  - "International Law and the Mexican Oil Conflict" (unpublished), Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 35)
  - "Kurzgeschichte" (unpublished), Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 36)
  - "Memorandum on the law concerning hostages", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 37)
  - "Monolog mit dem Verfassungsschutz", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 38)
  - "Ostpolitik: New Rapallo or Gateway to Détente?", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 39)
  - Reader's reports on books and articles for publishers, Undated (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 40)
  - "Reasons of the Failure of the League's System for the Protection of Minorities" (unpublished), Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 41)
  - "Recent International Ideologies" (unpublished), Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 42)
  - "Revolutionary and Post-revolutionary Forces Determining the Growth of Nationalism", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 43)
  - "Revolutionary Propaganda as an Instrument of Foreign Politics. A Study of the Use of Subversive Mass Propaganda in the International Relations of States", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 44)
  - "Seltsames Zwischenspiel", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 45)
  - "Solution By Delay - Ideas for the Berlin Situation", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 46)
  - "Some legal and political aspects of non-recognition", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 47)
  - "Staaten-Lexikon", Undated; Typescript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 48)
  - "Theories of international law", Undated; Manuscript (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous early manuscripts, 1930s (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 50)
  - "Zur Frage des Wahlrechts von Irrenanstaltsinsassen", 1932 June; Clipping (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 51)
  - "Zwiegespräch in dieser Zeit", early 1933 (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 52)
  - "Beiträge zum Problem der Identität des Staates", 1935; Reprints (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 53)
  - "Das Recht im Stufenbau der Seinsschichten", 1935; Reprints (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 54)
  - "Eine neue Wendung in der Meerengenfrage", 1936; Reprint (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 55)
  - "Le problem de la naissance de l'Etat et la decision du Tribunal Arbitral Mixte germane-polonais du 1er août 1929", 1936; Reprints (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 56)
  - "Le sujet de droit en droit international public", 1936; Reprints (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 57)
  - "Das Meerengenstatut von Montreux", 1937; Reprint (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 58)
  - "Recht und Realdialektik", 1937; Reprints (Box 9 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 59)
  - "Le conflit sino-japonais devant la Société des Nations", 1938; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 1)
  - Das Recht im Stufenbau der Seinsschichten. Dissertation, 1938; Bound typescript (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 2)
  - Bristler, Eduard. "La doctrine nationale-socialiste du droit des gens", 1938; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 3)
  - The National Socialist Doctrine of International Law, 1938; Bound typescript (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 4)
  - "Einige Bemerkungen zur Grundlegung des Völkerrechts", 1939; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 5)
  - "The National Socialist Doctrine of International Law and the Problems of International Organization", 1939; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 6)
  - "Bolshevist and National Socialist Doctrines of International Law", 1940 February; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 7)
  - "Germany May Be Ripe For Actual Democracy If She Loses This War", 1940 March 24; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 8)
  - "Nazism Is Seen As 'Genuine Revolution' Bent Only On Power", 1940 May 19; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 9)
  - "Victorious Nazism Seen As 'New Sparta', Rest of Europe Only 'Helots'", 1940 June 02; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 10)
  - "Expropriation of Alien Property", 1941 February; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 11)
  - "Remarks by Mr. John H. Herz", 1941 April 24-1941 April 26; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 12)
  - Poetry in bound volume, 1941 June 28 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 13)
  - "Alternative Proposals to Democracy: Naziism [sic]", 1941 July; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 14)
  - "Power Politics and World Organization", 1942 December; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 15)
  - "Law of War and the Crisis of International Relations", 1943 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 16)
  - "German Administration Under the Nazi Régime", 1946 August; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 17)
  - "The Fiasco of Denazification in Germany", 1948 December; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 18)
  - "Gedanken zu Thomas Manns 'Doktor Faustus'", 1949 January 29; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 19)
  - "Die Verfassung des Staates Israel", 1949 March 29; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 20)
  - "Neo-Malthusianismus", 1949 July 02; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 21)
  - "Notes on Mann's Doktor Faustus", 1949 Fall; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 22)
  - "Der Neger in Amerika", 1949 August 06; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 23)
  - "Idealist Internationalism and the Security Dilemma", 1950 January; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 24)
  - "Political Ideas and Political Reality", 1950 June; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 25)
  - "Macht, Mächtegleichgewicht, Machtorganisation im Atomzeitalter", 1951; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 26)
  - "Eisenhower inaugural", 1952 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 27)
  - "The Problem of Successorship in Dictatorial Régimes", 1952; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 28)
  - "Die Lehre vom Mächtegleichgewicht in moderner Sicht", 1952 August; Photocopy (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 29)
  - "Evidence from a Tapped Wire", 1954 March 15; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 30)
  - Interviews with high civil servants in West Germany, conducted for the RAND Corporation, 1953 July-1953 September; Transcripts, notes (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 31)
  - Political Views of the German Civil Service, 1954 June 02; Bound mimeograph (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 32)
    Report made to RAND Corporation.
  - "German Officialdom Revisited: Political Views and Attitudes of the West German Civil Service", 1954 October; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 33)
  - "Rise and Demise of the Territorial State", 1957 July; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 34)
  - "Politische Theorie in amerikanischer Sicht", 1957 November; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 35)
  - "Hauptprobleme des Völkerrechts im Atomzeitalter", 1959; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 36)
  - "International Politics in the Technological Age. An Analysis of the Role of Acceleration and Petrification in World Affairs", 1959 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 37)
  - "Able Statesmanship ...in Short Supply", 1959 May 04; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 38)
  - "Staatstheorie - deutsch und amerikanisch", 1959 June; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 39)
  - "As Coexistence Reduces Tensions..." (excerpt), 1959 October 17; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 40)
  - "Notes from an Egghead's Scrapbook", ca. 1960 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 41)
  - "Balance System and Balance Policies in a Nuclear and Bipolar Age", 1960; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 42)
  - "East Germany: Progress and Prospects", 1960 Summer; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 43)
  - "Disarmament ... Or Arms Control?", 1962 Spring; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 44)
  - "Die sehr fragwürdige Rolle der atomaren Abschreckung" (excerpt), 1962 April 16; Clipping (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 45)
  - "The Impact of the Scientific-Technological Process in International Relations", 1964 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 46)
  - "Sinn und Sinnlosigkeit der Beschwichtigungspolitik", 1964; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 47)
  - "The Relevancy and Irrelevancy of Appeasement", 1949 September-November; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 48)
  - "Kleine Dreigroschen - Musik 1965 oder Vom Sinn des Menschen", ca. 1965 (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 49)
  - "The Formation of the Grand Coalition", 1965; Photocopy (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 50)
  - "Otto Kirchheimer, †22.11.1965", 1966; Reprint (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 51)
  - "In Memoriam Otto Kirchheimer", 1966 September; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 52)
  - "Auswirkungen des wissenschaftlich-technischen Prozesses auf die internationalen Beziehungen", 1967; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 53)
  - "Vietnam - Exception, or Pattern for Future US Policy?", 1967 April; Mimeographed copy (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 54)
  - "The Impact of the Technological-Scientific Process on the International System", 1968; Photocopy (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 55)
  - "International Relations: Ideological Aspects", 1968; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 56)
  - "Stagnationsfaktoren der modernen Gesellschaft", 1968; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 57)
  - "The Territorial State Revisited", 1968; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 58)
  - "Amerika - Land ohne Alternative?", 1969; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 59)
  - "Otto Kirchheimer. An Introduction to His Life and Work", 1969; Reprints (Box 10 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 60)
    Co-authored with Erich Hula.
  - "'Unsterblichkeit' - Gedanken über Glanz und Elend der Sterblichen", 1970; Reprints (Box 11 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 1)
  - "A Statement by the Issue Editor", 1970 July (Box 11 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 2)
    Magazine issue.
  - "Relevancies and Irrelevancies in the Study of International Relations", 1971; Reprints (Box 11 (6-Essayistic writings, poetry, short ), Folder 3)